myinvestmentideas.com 2019-12-19

# Privacy Policy | Myinvestmentideas.com

**Updated Privacy Policy (August-2019)**

* * *

**Who we are?**

Our website address is: [https://myinvestmentideas.com](https://myinvestmentideas.com/).

**What personal data we collect and why we collect it?**  
**Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: [https://automattic.com/privacy/](https://automattic.com/privacy/). After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment

**Media**

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

**Contact forms**

Cookies: If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.  
If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

**Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

**Analytics**

**Who we share your data with?**

This is used only to share latest posts on this blog and any emails related to promotional activities. We do not share this information with 3rd parties. We respective your privacy.

 **How long we retain your data?**  
If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). 

Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

**What rights you have over your data?**

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

**Where we send your data?**  
Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

**Additional information**

**Our contact information:** For any specific queries, you can reach out to suresh@myinvestmetideas.com.  
**How we protect your data:** We don’t share your data with 3rd parties.  
**What automated decision making and/or profiling we do with user data:** We analyse visitors choice about various investment products

**Privacy Policy Updated Prior to May-2018 and still valid in some cases**

* * *

At [myinvestmentideas.com](https://myinvestmentideas.com/), the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us (See this article to learn more about Privacy Policies.). This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by [myinvestmentideas.com](https://myinvestmentideas.com/) and how it is used.

**Log Files**  
Like many other Web sites, [myinvestmentideas.com](https://myinvestmentideas.com/) makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**  
[myinvestmentideas.com](https://myinvestmentideas.com/) does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on [myinvestmentideas.com](https://myinvestmentideas.com/).
  * Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to [myinvestmentideas.com](https://myinvestmentideas.com/) and other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – [https://policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy/update)

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on [myinvestmentideas.com](https://myinvestmentideas.com/) send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

[myinvestmentideas.com](https://myinvestmentideas.com/) has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. [myinvestmentideas.com’s](https://myinvestmentideas.com/) privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.
